# **Richard Hendriks**

richard.hendriks@mail.com | http://richardhendricks.example.com | San Francisco, California

#### **SUMMARY**

Richard hails from Tulsa. He has earned degrees from the University of Oklahoma and Stanford. (Go Sooners and Cardinal!) Before starting Pied Piper, he worked for Hooli as a part time software developer. While his work focuses on applied information theory, mostly optimizing lossless compression schema of both the length-limited and adaptive variants, his non-work interests range widely, everything from quantum computing to chaos theory. He could tell you about it, but THAT would NOT be a "length-limited" conversation!

### SKILLS AND TECH

- Web Development: HTML, CSS, Javascript.
- Compression: Mpeg, MP4, GIF.

## **EXPERIENCE**

Pied Piper CEO/President Dec 2013 — Dec 2014

- Build an algorithm for artist to detect if their music was violating copy right infringement laws
- Successfully won Techcrunch Disrupt
- Optimized an algorithm that holds the current world record for Weisman Scores

### **VOLUNTEERING**

CoderDojo Teacher Jan 2012 — Jan 2013

Awarded 'Teacher of the Month'

#### **PROJECTS**

• **Miss Direction:** Won award at AIHacks 2016. Built by all women team of newbie programmers. Using modern technologies such as GoogleMaps, Chrome Extension and Javascript.

# **EDUCATION**

## University of Oklahoma

Jun 2011 — Jan 2014

Bachelor - Information Technology, GPA: 4.0

#### **PUBLICATIONS**

## Video compression for 3d media

Oct 2014

#### **AWARDS**

## Digital Compression Pioneer Award, Techcrunch

Nov 2014

### **INTERESTS**

• Wildlife: Ferrets, Unicorns